本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第五集』
翻译  Jasmine雪
翻译  LyraL
翻译  ala365
翻译  苏小黛
时间轴  veryink
校对  苏小黛
后期  渔夫
特效  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
艾克斯卡利伯
Excalibur!
不
No!
梅林走多久了
How long has Merlin been gone?
上次见他是四天前的事了
Four nights since we last saw him.
你觉得他会回来吗
Do you think he's coming back?
-不知道  -他为你取来了宝剑
- I don't know. - He got you that sword.
他不会就此弃你不顾的
He wouldn't just desert you after that.
要是梅林的话  一切皆有可能
Can't predict anything when it comes to Merlin.
你觉得他有计划吗  他知道他在做什么吗
Do you think he has a plan? Really knows what he's doing?
希望有吧
Huh! I hope so.
或许我们该停下  等雨停了再走
Maybe we should stop. Wait till it passes.
得了吧  这么点雨就难住我们的国王了
Come on. Don't tell me the king's worried by a bit of rain.
骑马再走几个小时就到卡米洛特了
Camelot's only a few hours' ride away.
我们得继续前进  走吧  我们比赛
We should keep going. Come on, I'll race you. Ya!
停停停
Stop, stop, stop!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
帮帮我  有人要杀我父亲
Help me! My father, he's going to kill him!
在哪儿  带我们去
Where? Show us.
走哪边
Which way?
-那边  -我们走  驾
- That way. - Come on. Ya!
驾  快走
Ya! Come on!
-那边  -快走
- Over there! - Come on! Ya!
把他吊起来
Take him up!
-放开他  -父亲
- Let him go! - Father!
放开他  这是你们国王的命令
Let him go! Your king demands it!
好吧  放他下来  放他下来
All right, take him down! Take him down!
-父亲  -帮我扶他进去
- Father! - Help me get him inside.
-为什么  他是个杀人犯  -照我说的做
- Why? He's a murderer! - You do as I say!
他杀了我哥哥  他该被吊死在这树上
He's murdered my brother! He should be hanging from this tree!
我们做的是正义之事
We're just taking what's right here.
没有国王的命令你们不能为所欲为
You'll take nothing without word from your king!
-这村叫什么  -埃斯汉姆  陛下
- What village is this? - Exham, sire.
这不需劳您大驾
Well, this needn't concern you.
我们可以处理自己的问题
We deal with our own problems.
我们不想耽搁您的行程
We don't want to detain you.
对不起  父亲  对不起
I'm sorry, Father. I'm sorry.
-这是怎么回事  -我们发现他
- How did this start? - We caught him
在我哥哥的尸体旁  手里拿着石头
over my brother's body with a rock in his hand and blood
脸上还有血迹  我们都看到了
on his face. We all saw it,
对吧  大伙儿  他是杀人凶手  陛下
didn't we, lads? He's a murderer, sire.
我们只是想伸张正义
We just want what's right.
我们都希望如此
Then we both agree on that.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
凯特琳
Katelyn.
求你了
Please.
别让他们这么做
Don't let them do this.
-这里的头领是谁  -我哥哥  韦德
- Who's the head man here? - My brother, Wade,
被这人杀害的那个人  就是这里的头领
the man he killed, he was head man.
现在应该是我了  大家都叫我尤恩
I suppose it falls to me now. They call me Ewan.
找几个人陪你
Choose a few men to accompany you.
-陪我  去哪儿  -卡米洛特
- Accompany me? Where? - Camelot.
等他恢复到可以为自己辩护了
You'll present your grievances
你可以向他声讨正义
against this man once he's fit to talk for himself.
陛下  我们可以自己处理好
I'm telling you, sire, we can deal with this on our own.
你们不需要这么做
And I'm telling you you don't need to!
你被复仇冲昏头脑时
You can't dispense justice
是不可能做到公平公正的
when your mind is clouded by revenge!
遵命  您听到所发生的事后
Of course. When you hear what happened, you'll come
会做出正确的决定的
to the right decision.
好  去选你的人
Yeah, then choose your men.
明早我们会在卡米洛特详细了解此事
We'll hear it all at Camelot tomorrow morning.
你确定要这么做吗
Are you sure about this?
此地并非卡米洛特的领地
Camelot's shadow only stretches so far.
那今天就会扩张了
Then today it stretches a little further.
我们走
Come on.
还是觉得很难控制吗
Still finding it hard to control?
你无权随心所欲的在我身边晃悠
You do not have the liberty to walk in on me whenever you please.
我的善心没到这个程度
Charity doesn't extend that far.
是这样吗  善心而已
Is that what it is? Charity?
我不需要你  西比尔  再也不需要你了
I don't need you for anything, Sybil. Not anymore.
哦  我觉得你需要
Oh, I think you do.
看看你  被一群陌生人围绕着
Look at you here, surrounded by strangers.
我是唯一真正了解你的人
I'm the only one who truly understands you.
为什么是伊格兰
Why Igraine?
我很好奇  为什么是她
Why her, I wonder?
很明显啊
It's very clear.
这样我可以进入卡米洛特  接近亚瑟
So I can get into Camelot, get close to Arthur,
然后杀了他
and kill him.
然后呢
But then what?
然后我会登上王位  那本来就是属于我的
And then I take the crown, which is rightfully mine.
再然后呢
And after that?
一如既往  你还是不够深谋远虑
As usual, you haven't thought far enough ahead.
我的时间全用来思考了
I have done nothing but think.
你没有  你需要朋友
No you haven't. You need friends.
-我不需要  -盟友
- No, I don't. - Allies.
我试过和人结盟  但失败了
I tried an alliance. It failed.
摩根  没有朋友与盟友
Morgan, without allies and friends, the throne will be
在你坐上王位前  它就会被人夺走了
taken from you before you even sit in it.
你对政治一无所知
You know nothing about politics.
没人知道你  摩根
Nobody knows you, Morgan.
他们都知道亚瑟  但不知道你是谁
They all know of Arthur, but not you.
他们知道我是尤瑟的女儿
They know I'm Uther's daughter.
尤瑟的女儿  亚瑟的姐姐
Uther's daughter, Arthur's sister--
你不能总是通过别人来定义自己
you can't be defined by others.
人们需要了解你本人
People need to know you for yourself.
我不会再和军阀达成协议了
I won't form any more pacts with warlords.
不是军阀  是商人和长者们
Not warlords; merchants; village elders.
商人和长者
Merchants and village elders?
这些人该成为我的盟友
These should be my allies?
他们是普通人  而且有影响力
They are ordinary and they are influential.
我跨海而来
I travelled here across the sea,
一路上  我留意过他人的言论
and all that way, I listened to the talk.
没人提起过你
Nobody talks of you.
有人谈论过亚瑟
Some talk of Arthur.
但绝大多数人都在谈论自己的恐慌
But most talk about their fear.
他们再也不认识自己的国家了
They don't recognize their country anymore,
这让他们很恐惧
and it frightens them.
恐惧是最有力的武器
There is nothing more powerful than fear.
你还记得恐惧的感觉吗
You remember what it's like to be frightened.
还记得当有人来帮你驱走那恐惧时
And when someone comes, takes that fear away,
你是多么敬爱他们
how you love them for it.
多么崇拜他们吗
How you worship them.
因此  你需要结交新朋友
So you will make new friends.
届时人们谈论的就将是摩根女士了
And then all the talk will be of the Lady Morgan.
赞颂她了解民生疾苦
How she understands the suffering of the people,
赞颂她是他们亲密的朋友
how she is their friend,
同情她合法的王位
and how she has been robbed
被人野蛮的抢走
of her legitimate claim to the crown.
他们不会认为我在分担他们的痛苦
They won't see that I share their suffering;
他们只会把我当做亚瑟的狗腿
they'll see me as Arthur's lackey,
认为我在试探是否有叛徒
sniffing out traitors.
你只需做到热情好客  平易近人就行了
You'll be welcoming and gracious,
其他事自会迎刃而解
and the rest will take care of itself.
他们就快到了
They'll be here soon.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
昨晚我发出了些请柬
I had invitations sent out last night.
你得盛情款待他们
You're giving quite a feast in their honour.
摩根小姐待客如此慷慨  一如其善心
The Lady Morgan's hospitality is bountiful, like her charity.
你太自作主张了
You're giving far too many orders.
就放纵我这一次吧
Indulge me just this once.
如果失败了  就赶我走吧
If it fails, turn me out.
戴这条
Wear this one.
不是吧  又来了
Not again.
走开
Away.
人越来越多了
More people.
他们睡在哪儿啊
Where are they supposed to sleep?
谁负责组织这里
Who's organizing this?
问得好  你觉得呢  小羊
Good question. What do you reckon, goat?
你的山羊又闯进我房间了
Your goat was in my chambers again.
这星期已经是第二次了
That's the second time this week.
-抱歉  女士  -看好你的羊
- Sorry, My Lady. - Keep your goat under control.
梅林
Merlin?
不
No!
现在不行
Not now.
还不是时候
Not a good time right now.
让我一个人呆着
Leave me alone.
这事你打算这么处理
How are we going to judge this?
到大厅见我  带上高文  欧菲尔斯
Meet me in the hall with Gawain, Ulfius,
布拉提斯和里昂提斯
Brastias, and Leontes.
我会告诉你们怎么做的
I'll explain how it'll work.
真希望梅林在
I wish Merlin were here.
你是将军  我是国王  我们不需要他
You're the marshal. I'm the king. We don't need him.
我知道我们在做什么  去叫人吧
I know what we do. Fetch the men.
-殿下  -桂妮维尔
- Your Highness. - Guinevere.
你可能注意到了  有点问题
You might have noticed there's a problem.
每天有越来越多的人前来  这很好
Every day more people come, which is good,
但我们仍像住在临时居所里一样
but we're still living like it's temporary,
可这儿并非临时居所
which it isn't.
我们是要在此长期生活的  对吗
We're here to stay, right?
是的  所以呢
Right. So?
这里没有秩序可言
Well, there's no order.
我们怎么养活这么多人  他们在哪睡觉
How do we feed people? Where do they sleep?
这里的人都有所需求
Everybody here needs something,
但是他们也可以有所奉献
but they can also offer something.
我打算把这里弄得井井有条
I'm going to make everything more organized.
除非您反对
Unless you object.
我不反对  祝你好运
I don't object. You have my blessing.
尤瑟遇害
Uther's murder...
王国无主
...robbed the country of its king.
旧的秩序被打破
The old certainties are gone.
新的秩序正在建立
A new beginning is being forged.
一切都在变化当中
And while everything is changing,
在此动荡之时
in such flux, it's...
很容易令人觉得  被忽视了
it's easy to feel... overlooked.
我不希望你们觉得自己被遗忘了
I don't want you to think that you're being forgotten.
我愿向你们证明  我是你们的朋友
I would like to prove myself a friend,
我向你们保证  你们有任何
and assure you that any fears
恐惧或是麻烦
or questions you may have
都可以向我倾诉
can be safely shared with me.
说吧  大人  我们得马上说出实情
Now, Lord, we need to speak the truth, now!
我们感激国王陛下的姐姐
We are all grateful to the king's sister
如此的恩典和仁慈  但我代表大家表示
for her grace and kindness. But I speak for us all
我们对亚瑟的统治都真心感到满足和欣喜
when I say we are truly content and rejoice in Arthur's rule.
我也是
As do I.
在卡米洛特设立法庭
Tribunals for justice here at Camelot?
我们处于王国的中央
We're at the center of the realm.
我们的价值观应该传播到每一个村落去
Our values have to spread out into every community.
这些村落都有他们自己的习俗了
These communities already have their own way of doing things.
我们也看到他们的习俗了
We saw their way of doing things.
他连为自己辩护的机会都没有就会被杀了
He'd have been dead before he had a chance to defend himself.
那你要我们做什么
So why do you need us?
国王应当独立进行裁决
Surely a king sits alone in matters of judgment.
再说  我们有何资格评判他人
And anyway, who are we to judge?
我们自己都杀人如麻
We all kill plenty.
建立这个法庭是为了查明缘由
The purpose of the tribunal is to discover the cause.
亚里士多德归结人行为的七大缘由
Aristotle's seven causes:
巧合  天性  强迫  习惯
chance, nature, compulsion, habit,
理智  激情和欲望
reason, passion, and desire.
你说有人看到凶手打死人了
You said the killer was seen delivering the blow.
要是这样  探寻缘由还有何意义
What does cause matter if that was the case?
缘由很重要
Cause is everything.
我们不知道谁先动的手  谁是正当防卫
We don't know who attacked who, who acted in self-defence.
如果我们能查明打斗的缘由
If we discover the cause of the fight,
就能推测出真相
we'll reason the truth.
我们要一起讨论听到的证词  并作出决定
We'll discuss what we've heard and decide,
无论判他无罪还是有罪  都一起决定
innocent or guilty, together as one.
惩罚方式呢  也一起决定吗
And what about punishment? To be decided by all of us?
不  这个责任我自己来担
No, that burden shall be mine alone.
交出你们的武器
Surrender your blades.
你们所有人
All of you.
你的剑
Your sword.
-我们不想惹事  -那就用不上匕首
- We don't want any trouble. - Then you won't need the dagger.
你过去后  待着别说话  懂吗
You stay silent in there. Understand?
科尔弗请站在这里  凯特琳  坐吧
Colfur, stand, please. Katelyn, take a seat.
陛下  说真的  我们不想
Sire, really, we don't want to
这样浪费您的时间
waste your time like this.
我们知道如何处理我们村的事务
We know how to deal with our own affairs.
您这样关注我们让我们深感不安
We're embarrassed to have your eyes on us
您一定还有许多其他事物要处理
when there must be so much else you could be doing.
你不用不安  我们就是来处理此事的
You don't need to be embarrassed. This is what we're here to do.
此次听证会的目的是处理埃斯汉姆村
The purpose of this hearing is to address the murder
头领韦德被杀一案  并对此案中被目击
of Exham's head man, Wade, and decide upon a suitable punishment
袭击被害人的科尔弗  做出适当的判罚
for the man who was seen to attack him, Colfur.
今天是卡米洛特的首次听证会
Today is our first hearing in Camelot.
我相信以后还会有更多的
I'm sure there'll be many more.
作为你们的国王
As you king,
我旨在让整个国家的公平正义
it is my intention to apply the justice
始于今日
throughout the realm that begins here today.
尤恩  你先说
Ewan, you speak first.
讲讲你们村和你的哥哥韦德的事
Tell us about your village and your brother, Wade.
我不知该从何说起
Well, I don't know where to begin.
我哥哥是个好人
My brother was a good man.
我们的村子很平静
Our village is quiet.
在他出现以前  我们从没有过
We never had any trouble till the likes of him
任何纷争
came along.
此话怎讲
And why is that?
他就爱唱反调
Well, he's a naysayer, isn't he?
总是抱怨这  抱怨那
Always complaining about something.
总想纠结人一起惹是生非
Trying to band people together, cause trouble.
你对此有何解释
What do you have to say to that?
我爱说什么就说什么
I don't guard my words.
别人爱听则听  反之亦然
Them that like it, like it. Them that don't, don't.
你们是怎么打起来的
Why did the fight start?
重要的是怎么结束的
All that matters is how it finished,
韦德罪有应得
and Wade got what was coming to him.
如果你是想问谁先动手的  是我
But if you're asking who landed the first blow, it was me.
韦德最初为何会去找你
Why did Wade come to see you in the first place?
他向我哥哥租地  他欠了他租金
He rented land from my brother. He owed him tithes.
他都几个月没交租了
Well, he hadn't seen hide nor hair of payment in months.
韦德是因为这个去找你吗  去收租
Is that why Wade was there? To collect his tithes?
如果是  我没打算给他钱
If he was, I wasn't of a mind to pay him.
你住在他的土地上  你该给他钱的
You were on his land, you should pay him.
我放个屁还给他吧
He can have the steam off my shite before I give him anything!
你听到了吗
You see?
我哥一年前就可以把他赶走了
My brother could have thrown him off that land a year past.
他有这打算
He had a mind to.
可他心太软了
He was too soft.
好心却没好报啊
Well, look where it got him.
不必多费唇舌  我不感兴趣
Before you open your mouth, I'm not interested.
救赎的事还是省省吧
Past saving.
我不是来救赎你的
I'm not here to save you.
怎么称呼
What do I call you?
托莫尔  你呢
Tomal. You?
你是个雇佣兵
Am I right in thinking
我没说错吧
you're a mercenary?
没错
Yes.
你身手好吗
Are you a good one?
至少我还活着
I'm still alive.
-你要杀谁  -我不想杀任何人
- Who do you want killed? - I don't want anyone killed.
那干嘛
What, then?
把人打到能看出伤痕和血迹就行了
The sort of attack that leaves marks and blood.
-好办  但为何  -干嘛  你还管这个
- Easy. But why? - What, do you care?
不管
No.
那我们就算说定了
Then we understand each other.
这世界是怎么了啊
What's happening to this world?
会变成地狱的
It's goin' to hell.
上帝会解脱我们的
God will deliver us.
不见得
I doubt it.
告诉我你想打谁
But tell me who you want beaten.
我
Me.
来吃的了
Food.
你在干嘛啊
What are you doing?
我需要一个房间  我连个房间都没有
I needed a room. Didn't have a room.
到处都好吵
Too much noise everywhere else.
到处人声鼎沸
Noise and people.
这都是你弄的吗
Is this all you?
我需要思考
Needed to think.
最近都没时间思考了
Haven't had time to think lately.
你在颤抖
You're shaking.
梅林  你在流汗
Merlin, you're sweating.
事后总会这样
That always happens afterwards.
什么事后
After what?
你做了什么
这些伤是怎么来的
How did you get those injuries?
我自找的
I asked for them.
梅林  你说的我都听不懂
Merlin, you're not making any sense.
巫师不需要被理解
Wizards don't need to.
亚瑟在大堂  在主持一场审讯
Arthur's in the great hall, holding a trial.
他干嘛啊
What's he doing that for?
则就是我想说的
This is what I mean.
不管你计划得多好  人们总是
Plan all you like, but people...
没错  人们总会来加以阻碍
Yes, they get in the way.
出来吧
Come outside.
不行  不  不  不  不  不
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no.
还有很多事要做
Too much to do.
梅林  亚瑟需要你
Merlin, Arthur needs you!
他需要你
He needs you!
好了  陛下
Well, Sire,
该听的您都听到了
you've heard everything you need to hear.
科尔弗承认是他先动手  我们都看到了
Colfur admits he started the fight, and we all saw him
他杀韦德  此事毫无争议
kill Wade. There's no dispute here.
我们需要了解缘由才能做出公平的判罚
We need to understand the reason to fairly decide the punishment.
缘不缘由有什么关系
What's reason got to do with any of this?
不可对国王不敬  你会得到你要的正义的
Respect the king and you'll get your justice.
是因为你不肯向韦德缴租才起的争执吗
Did the fight start because you refused to pay Wade his tithe?
-回答国王的问话  -有什么意义
- Answer the king! - Why?
我在试着理解事情的始末
I'm trying to understand.
他来找我  我们打起来了
He came to me, we fought,
我用块石头把他脑袋砸烂了  就是这样
I smashed his head in with a rock. That's the fact of it.
你宁可被处死  也不肯说实话吗
Would you rather be executed than talk?
说不说有什么用
You think talking will make a difference?
你只是在利用我显示自己多公正
You're just using me here to test your justice.
这事完了以后你还会保护我们吗  不会
Are you going to stand guard when all this is over? No!
所以说不说都一样
So no point in talking!
陛下  这么做有什么用啊
Sire, what difference does any of this make?
我哥哥已经死了  他也该死
My brother's dead, and he deserves the same fate!
安静
Silence!
我们得休息一下
We need a break.
去吃点东西
Go get some food.
就是桩谋杀案  相互报复而已
It's murder. An eye for an eye.
-高文你说呢  -他交不起租
- Gawain? - He couldn't pay his tithe,
就杀了头领  这是冷血的谋杀
so he killed the head man. It's execution.
但科尔弗并没承认这一点
You know, Colfur didn't admit that.
他说的是如果韦德是去收租的
He said IF Wade was there for that,
他也不会给他
he wouldn't have been of a mind to pay him.
-这不一样吗  -不一样
- Same thing. - It's not.
你第二次问他的时候  他没回答
When you asked him again, he didn't respond.
如果韦德去找他是为了别的什么呢
What if Wade was there for something else?
亚瑟  这事已经太费神了
Arthur, this is becoming a distraction.
我们还有很多事要做呢
We have plenty we need to do.
处决了科尔弗  然后我们该干嘛干嘛吧
Execute Colfur, and let's get back to work.
你还是会被看做是一位强大的领导者
You'll still be seen as a strong leader.
她为什么要跑
Why did she run?
我们最初看到她的时候
When we first saw her?
她跑去求助吧
She was running for help.
不
No.
她是在逃跑
She was running away.
她的父亲正被攻击
Her father was being attacked.
她为什么不跑去其他村庄呢
Why didn't she go to any of the other villages?
当你问起科尔弗  韦德为什么去找他时
When you asked Colfur why Wade was there,
他和凯特琳对视了一眼
there was this look between Colfur and Katelyn.
似乎他不想让她说话
It was like he wanted to be sure she wouldn't speak.
摩根
Morgan!
天啊
Oh, my Lord!
西比尔
Sibyl.
我们在林子里找到她
She was found in the woods.
大家让开
Get away from her.
把她抬到她床上
Let's get her to her bed.
不  去我房间
No, my chamber.
连修女都被打了
The holy mother beaten
我们都不安全
none of us are safe.
快  去拿水和布
Run, fetch water and cloths!
他们看到了...
They see...
...你在和他们一起经受痛苦
...that you suffer with them.
还说我不懂政治吗
Now tell me I know nothing about politics.
别浪费时间  孩子
Don't waste the moment, child.
好好利用这机会
Use it.
去吧
Go.
去啊
我需要帮助
I need help.
你需要女人出马
You want a woman's touch?
是
Mm.
她不是求助而是逃生
She ran instead of getting help.
这没道理
It doesn't make sense.
我必须确定
I have to be sure.
我必须确定他是有罪  才能判他死刑
I can't sentence a man to death unless I'm sure.
他杀了另一个男人
He killed another man.
为何审判他会如此困扰你
Why does sentencing him bother you so much?
因为我想让我们的判决
Because I want our justice
比以前更严明  更公正
to be better than what's gone before.
因为我想  有时候
And because I think that sometimes maybe
人也许会为正当理由而犯错
people do the wrong thing for the right reasons.
这儿很美
It is beautiful.
我有时会来这里思考
I sometimes come here to think.
我以前从没见过大海
I've never seen the sea before.
亚瑟是个好人
Arthur's a good man.
他愿意倾听人们的疾苦
He listens to the people.
他真的关心大家
He really cares.
他帮不了我  没人帮得了
He can't help me. No one can.
这是我的错
It's my fault.
为什么
Why?
我逃跑了
I ran.
我父亲叫我快跑
My father told me to.
我们知道韦德快来了
We knew Wade was coming.
他来干嘛
What was he coming for?
我们的头领会享有每个女孩的贞操
The head man takes every girl as she becomes a woman.
不可能
No!
就是这回事
It's the way.
难道没人阻止吗
Do people not try and stop this?
我们斗不过韦德和尤恩的家族
You don't stand against Wade and Ewan's kin.
伊格兰说得对
Igraine was right.
是  这就是原因
Yes, this is why.
被她发现了
Heh... She finds out,
现在来打扰的人没完没了
and now it's an endless stream of visitors
还偏偏是在我想要思考的时候
just when I'm trying to think.
还有谁来过
Who else has been here?
那不是重点
Hmm? That's not the point.
你是说只有我吗
Huh... You mean just me?
是我在没完没了的打扰你
An endless stream of me? Hm!
你想要什么
What is it you want?
你就这样独自待这里
You were here all alone.
我需要时间
I needed some time.
这是什么
What is this?
我想把一切都列出来
I wanted to lay it all out.
这些都是什么意思
What does it all mean?
那代表了第一波...
Oh, that just shows the first wave is...
...业已完成
...ostensibly complete.
但我们已经落后了
But we've fallen behind.
还有很多事情需要做
There's so much more to do.
比如建个图书馆
The library.
第一波  是什么意思
What do you mean, "First wave"?
就是带你来这里
Well, getting you here--
占领卡米洛特  招募人才
occupying Camelot, recruiting people.
你的审讯怎么样
How's your trial?
你来吗
Will you come?
不去
No.
为什么
Why?
因为你已有了计划
You had the big idea.
好好干吧
See it through.
我会的
I will.
很好
Good.
我很快就会好起来
I'll be fine soon.
我只需要...
I just needed...
...就像现在这样
...this.
我会关注你的
I'll be watching.
又被伏击
Yet another ambush.
这是个严重的问题...
This is a serious trouble...
...出门没有安全保障
...travel about without protection.
告诉女人们...
Tell the women...
摩根小姐
Lady Morgan.
我必须道歉
I must apologize.
不  不
No, no, no. No, no, no.
不必这样  她怎么样了
Not at all. How is she?
有人照料着她
She's being attended.
你们得原谅我
You'll have to forgive me.
她就像我的母亲
She's been a mother to me
从我小时候就开始照顾我
since I was a little girl.
怎么会这样
How can this happen?
请
Please.
喝吧
Drink.
谢谢
Thank you.
她的马有彭德拉根的标记
Her horse was carrying the Pendragon symbol.
她带了我们的印旗吗
She was wearing our colours?
但这本该能保护我们啊
But... but this is our protection.
我商旅途中一直执此印旗
I fly this banner along my trading routes.
但还是被袭击
It's still attacked.
这印旗飘遍我们的村庄
The banner is flown over my village,
可我们的粮仓还是被抢
and yet our grain stores are robbed,
我们的姑娘还是被掳走
our young women are taken.
到处都没王法  无法无天
There's no control. None at all.
我们都是忠诚的子民
We are all loyal subjects.
这...这...
Well, this... this...
...这可称不上保护
...this is not protection.
我们理解  他是您弟弟
We understand he is your brother.
但王土已然混乱
But the land moves further into chaos
并日趋恶化
every day.
这才是真相
And that is the real truth.
我不会听之任之
I will not let this happen.
我发誓
I will not!
还有人也感觉不公吗
Are there others who feel betrayed?
是的  有很多人
Yes, there are others.
我要代表我们所有人
I will send a messenger
送个信给我弟弟
to my brother to represent all of us.
当他知道这些  他会有所表示
When he knows of this, he will act.
我知道他会有所补偿  相信他
I know he will want to make redress. Have faith in him.
同时
In the meantime,
告诉其他有此遭遇之人
send word to others who feel this way.
叫他们今晚来彭德拉根的城堡
Tell them to come to Castle Pendragon tonight.
告诉他们国王会给大家一个答复
Tell them the king will come to his sister's call.
我要派人去送信吗
Shall I send for the messenger?
别麻烦了
Don't bother.
我们在等什么
So what are we waiting for?
他现在就该被处决了
He should be dead and buried by now.
和你的人一起等着
Go wait with your people.
这有何用
How does this help?
我拿起石头  砸了他的头
I got a rock, I smashed it on his head.
这是我自作自受
I deserve what I get.
大家必须了解实情
The people have to know.
我可以宽恕你  因为有正当理由
I can spare you; there was justification.
但大家得知道为什么
But the people have to know why.
不  我说过我不想那样
No. I've told you no.
如果你不说出来  这种事还会继续
If you don't speak about this, it will keep on happening.
那与我无关
That's not my responsibility.
那一切怎么会改变
Then how does anything ever change?!
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
为什么
Why?
你出去一下  凯特琳
Go out, Katelyn.
不
No.
出去  拜托
I said go out. Please.
韦德的家族...
Wade's family...
...拥有村庄所有的土地
...owns all the land the village is on.
每种庄稼的第一季收成都归他们
They get the first realm of every crop.
秋季  他们会开垦
They plough the first furrow
每个农场的第一条田沟
of every farm come autumn.
我结婚的前一晚
The night before my wedding,
韦德和尤恩的父亲来行使他的权利
Wade and Ewan's father claimed his tithe.
我不是本地人  我没听说过...
I was an outsider. I... I hadn't heard...
...头领可以享有每个女人的初夜
...head man was always the first for every woman.
凯特琳的母亲...在我们婚后两天...
Katelyn's mother... told me...
...告诉了我实情
...two days after we were married.
她生凯特林琳的时候死于难产
She died giving birth to Katelyn.
凯特琳  韦德和尤恩是...
Katelyn, Wade, and Ewan are...
...血亲
...kin.
韦德和尤恩并不在意
Wade and Ewan don't care.
那些兄弟占有了每个姑娘
Those brothers come for every girl.
你们为什么不离开呢
Then why didn't you leave?
我什么都没做错
I did nothing wrong!
你必须说出事实
You have to speak.
得阻止这样的事
This has to stop!
不行
I can't!
凯特琳不知道她不是我亲生的
Katelyn doesn't know she's not mine.
如果她知道了  我会永远失去她
If she knew, she... I'll have lost her!
看看我
Oh, look at me,
老大不小了  哭得像个小孩
a grown man, crying like a baby.
连结你们的不是血脉
It's not blood that ties you together;
而是你们共同的回忆
it's the memories you share.
是你教授她的一切
Everything you taught her,
是你为她放弃的一切
everything you gave up for her--
那是你的爱
that's your love;
那才是她所在意的
that's what flows through her.
告诉她  你会看到她有多爱你
Tell her and you'll see how much she loves you.
我知道的
I know.
你以为村里的姑娘们
You think the girls in the village
不会谈论这些吗
don't talk about this?
我一直都知道
I've always known.
但是...
And...
...我从没有因此而不爱你
...I never loved you any the less.
你...是我的父亲
You... are my father.
韦德过来想占有她
Wade had come for her.
我叫她逃跑
And I told her to run.
我叫她忘记我
I told her to forget me
远离我  有多远跑多远
and get away-- as far away as she could.
我告诉他  别靠近我女儿
I told him I'd kill him
不然就杀了他
before I'd let him near my girl.
那就是争斗的原因
That's how the fight started.
你有什么要说的吗
Have you anything to say?
这些我们都知道
We knew all this.
那是我们的生存之道
That's the way we live.
你们村的习俗
The customs of your village
将不再延续
are no longer acceptable.
头领比其他人更努力劳作
The head man works harder than anyone.
他有权享有第一次成果
He's entitled to first fruit,
至今没一个国王更改这习俗
and no Christian boy king is ever gonna change that.
今天就改
It changes today.
祝你好运
Oh, good luck.
现在  做判决吧
Now give your verdict.
科尔弗将因此而被逐出埃斯汉姆村
Colfur is hereby banished from the village of Exham.
你们回去收拾一下
You may return to collect your belongings.
然后永远离开该村
Then leave the village permanently.
-谢谢  -谋杀  只判驱逐
- Thank you. - Banishment! For murder?
只判驱逐
Banishment for murder
因为他的本意只是要保护女儿的名节
whilst trying to protect his daughter's honour.
听证会到此结束
The hearing is finished.
-很遗憾  -什么意思
- Well, that's a shame. - Why?
如果这就是卡米洛特秉持的正义
'Cause if that's Camelot justice...
那你在王位上坐不了多久了
...you'll be a short time on the throne.
他并没需要我
He didn't need me.
谢谢你关注他
Thank you for checking on him.
有一个女孩死去了
There was a girl and she died.
是我的错
And it was my fault.
我本以为我能控制自己的意念
I thought I could control what I was trying to do.
你太孤僻了
You keep yourself too alone.
你为何如此介怀
Why does it bother you?
因为有时我能隐约看到
Because sometimes I see glimpses
你将成为什么样的人
of the man you might be.
你这么做都是为了我
You did all this for me?
为了你  我愿意做任何事
There is nothing I wouldn't do for you.
你今晚必须爆发  孩子
You must blaze tonight, child.
这都是你应得的
It's all yours to take.
爆发吧
So blaze.
他们对女人们所做的事
What they do to the women...
你觉得在其他村会有同样的情况吗
Do you think it happens in other villages?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许吧
Maybe.
无论如何
Wherever it is...
我们都要加以阻止
...we have to stop it.
一定
We will.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你去引导凯特琳
For what you did with Katelyn.
不必客气
You're welcome.
疼吗
Does it hurt?
-死不了  -骗子
- I'll be fine. - Liar.
你以前到底在伤口上擦了什么啊
What on earth did you use on it before?
-什么也没擦  -希望那剑值得你如此拼命
- Nothing. - Well, I hope that sword is worth it.
你为它受了这么多伤
After the amount of injuries you've got,
这剑最好能成为传奇
it had better become legendary.
那是把好剑  但要成为传奇
Ah, it's a great sword, but it'll only be...
必须用它做点传奇之事才行
...legendary if he does something legendary with it.
梅林
Merlin...
你到底是什么人
Who are you?
我该怎么回答
How am I supposed to answer that?
好吧  遇到亚瑟  甚至遇到乌瑟之前
All right, all right. Who were you before Arthur?
你是什么人
Before Uther?
跟现在一样
The same.
-你生在何处  -很重要吗
- Where were you born? - Does it matter?
不重要  但我好奇
It doesn't matter, but I'm interested.
你总是有所隐瞒
You hide.
即使再来这里之前  你也有所隐瞒
Even when you're not here, you hide.
-我无意隐瞒  -不  你有意
- I don't mean to. - Yes, you do.
那你呢
What about you?
你知道我的一切
You know everything about me.
康沃尔
Cornwall.
尤瑟
Uther.
然后到了这儿
Here.
但在康沃尔之前
But before Cornwall...
你又是什么样的人
Who were you then?
当时我很
I was...
坚强
...strong.
固执
Opinionated.
天真
Naive...
而且充满希望
...and full of hope.
生长在条件优渥之家
Living comfortably in a family with means.
你当时的梦想是什么
What did you dream of?
我梦想有一个能够平等待我的夫君
I dreamt of a husband who'd treat me as an equal.
你找到他了吗
Did you ever find him?
没有
No.
很遗憾
I'm sorry for that.
我也是
So am I.
-不行  -怎么了
- No! - What's the matter?
靠近我的人都会被焚烧致死
People who get close to me get burned.
你怎么会成为这种人的
How did you become such a man?!
-多上点酒  -是的  修女
- Be generous with the drink. - Yes, Holy Mother.
确保每个人都能吃好
Make sure everyone is well fed.
是你  你跟国王的姐姐同住
It's you. You live here with the king's sister?
不  我只是为了食物而来
No, I don't. I came for the food.
你在给侍女们下命令  你一定住在这里
You were giving orders to the servants. You live here.
为什么摩根的修女要付钱让我殴打她
Why does Morgan's nun pay me to beat the pulp out of her?
我需要一个栖身之所
I... needed a roof over my head.
这样能让他们心软
And this... persuaded them.
求你了  别对我妄加评判
Please. Don't judge me.
-东西都在这儿了吗  -是的  谢谢
- Is this everything? - Yes, sir. - Thank you.
你得赶不少路
You've got a lot of ground to cover.
最好别犯傻惹我出手
Don't make the mistake of taking me on.
我们有我们自己的规矩
You see, we have our own justice.
我也有我的  我母亲就曾被人强暴过
So do I. My mother knew what it was to be raped.
所以你们这种人  在我心里有着特殊的位子
So I keep a special place in my heart for people like you.
天高皇帝远  这里是我说了算
Your king doesn't rule around here; I do.
适可而止吧  多说多错
You the more you talk, the more trouble you're in.
我说科尔弗  你就是这种人么
So, Colfur, is this who you are?
躲在个毛头小子和他的武士身后
Hiding behind a boy king and his warriors? Eh, Colfur!
这个男人已经受到了处罚
This man has been banished!
我正在执行判决
And I'm carrying out his sentence.
请别妨碍我
Please don't get in my way.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
-..杀了我哥哥  -我最后一次警告你
- ...killed my brother. - This is your last warning!
滚回家去
Go back to your dwellings.
怎么着  大个子
What the matter, big man?
不敢跟我们打吗
Are you afraid to fight?
你会得到应有的处罚
Ah, you'll get your rightful punishment.
你女儿也将履行她的义务
And your girl will get her due.
就是他
Him.
区区小事
This is not a problem.
各位
My people.
欢迎今晚来到彭德拉根的城堡
I welcome you tonight to Castle Pendragon.
国王呢  他来了吗
Where's the king? Has he come?
很遗憾  他公务繁忙  无暇理会我
I'm sorry to say that he was too busy to talk to me.
什么
What?
他把我的信使打发回来了
He sent my messenger back
说他太忙  无暇顾及我们的担忧
with word that he was too busy to address our concerns.
-太  太忙  -我理解你们的心情
- Too... too busy? - I share your frustration.
我也无法再粉饰太平了
I cannot pretend otherwise.
我现在觉得
It seems to me now...
我们正处于绝壁之上
...that we stand on the very brink.
过去在我父亲的庇护下的一切安定
Everything that was once so secure
现在都受到了威胁
under my father's reign is now under threat.
我们全都身陷险境
All of us are in danger.
我对我弟弟绝无二心
I am loyal to my brother,
但我为将来担心  非常担心
but I fear the future. I fear it.
我问自己  若是国王忙得无暇理会我们
And I ask myself, what do we mean to the king
那我们对他来说究竟算什么
if he's too busy for us?
总算来了啊
Finally!
别傻站着  帮忙啊
Well, don't just stand there! Help me!
我说过科尔弗将被驱逐出这里
You were told Colfur was to be banished!
你以为你的话在这还能管用
You think your words mean anything here,
这可不是任凭你为非作歹的地方
in the real world?
-你对这里毫无贡献  -好好看看
- You've done nothing here.  - Look around you.
这里不再是你的村庄了
This is no longer your village.
我不会忙到置你们于不顾
I am not too busy for you.
我愿聆听你们的哀伤  并会感同身受
I hear your woes and they grieve me.
可经过今晚之事
But know that tonight,
我在此发誓
I make an oath,
我向你们保证
a pledge to you all that I will
我将以血肉之躯全力保护你们
protect you with my life's blood.
不列颠需要一个强大的领袖
Britain needs a strong leader.
没错
Yes.
我愿向你们证明自己的诚意
Let me prove myself to you.
你
You.
上来
Come here.
是他吗
Is this the man?
是的
Yes.
就是他打了我
That is the man who beat me.
不
No!
好
Yes!
我到哪都能活下来
I can go anywhere.
我可以东山再起  你阻止不了我
I can start again. You can't stop me.
你搬  我们会找到你
Move, and we'll find you.
你逃  我们会追捕你
Run, and we'll hunt you.
无论你在哪  卡米洛特都将如影随形
Wherever you are, Camelot will be your shadow.
为了所有被你伤害过的女子
You deserve to die
让你死十次都不足惜
ten times over for every woman you've harmed.
够了  高文
That's enough, Gawain.
你真不值得我弄脏自己的剑
You're not worth the cloth and oil to clean the blades.
从今以后  这个村里所有的女人
From today, every woman in this village is protected
都将受到我的人  我的徽旗的保护
by my men, by my flag.
如果有任何女人  任何人受到伤害
If harm falls to any woman, to anybody,
他们都将知道
they will know.
埃斯汉姆现在是卡米洛特的一部分了
Exham is now part of Camelot.
此人代表着所有曾偷窃过你们的人
This man is every man who stole from you.
代表所有曾恐吓过你们的人
Every man who terrorized you.
所有曾侵犯过你们妻女
Who violated your women and girls,
虐待过你们子嗣的人
and brutalized your sons.
此人代表着
This man is every man
所有曾令你们感到卑微  软弱  无能的人
who made you feel worthless, despised, and weak!
此人代表着所有曾践踏你们的尊严
This man is every man who robbed you of your dignity
让你们因身为这个国家的一员而感到耻辱的人
and made you ashamed to belong to this once great nation!
我  摩根  尤瑟之女
I, Morgan, daughter of Uther...
将他交由你们处置
...give him to you.
现在  履行你们的正义吧
Now take your justice!